# **Tshepo Thoriso Shale**

Proudly South African

Code B/08 Driver

in https://za.linkedin.com/in/tshepo-shale-398490184

# **Profile**

I.T., & Project Management Alumni, with over 5 years comprehensive experience, having a knack for achieving organizational goals. General Projects, Experienced I.T. Project Manager Driving Successful Project Delivery and Business Growth, a stellar I.T Operations enthusiast, and a hybrid-role activist.

## **Education**

# **Baccalaureus Technologiae Degree in Project**

02/2020 - 01/2022

Management, Central University of Technology

Bloemfontein, South Africa

Learning about Project Management trends and problem-solving skills, pairing them with stellar work ethics, majoring in Project Quality.

## National Diploma in information Technology,

02/2015 - 12/2019

Central University of Technology

Bloemfontein, South Africa

Coding and Programming in C#, ASP.Net, CSS, JavaScript, and HTML. Computer hardware and software, components of computers and how they work, as well as the different types of software that are used in business and industry.

Networking, Information systems, Security: Students learn about the different types of security threats that exist on computer networks, as well as the different methods that can be used to protect computer systems from these threats, and WebDev.

#### **Certificates**

MCSE in Windows Server 2016

**Microsoft Azure Fundamentals** 

Microsoft Security and Compliance Fundamentals

**SCRUM Master** 

National School of Governance (Introduction to Project Management)

iLearn Academy (Microsoft Office Suite)

Lean Six Sigma (White Belt)

**CISCO (CCNA: Routing & Switching)** 

# **Professional Experience**

**UVU Africa (CapaCiTi),** Candidate Full Stack Developer 07/2023 - present | Cape Town, South Africa

- Establishing the foundational structure of the website's user interface.
- Crafting user engagement and experience on web pages.
- Building the behind-the-scenes functionality of the website.
- Constructing servers and databases to enable various features.
- Guaranteeing seamless performance across different mobile platforms.

- Ensuring that the applications adapt well to various screen sizes.
- Collaborating closely with graphic designers to implement web design elements.
- Managing projects from initial concept to the final product.
- Creating and designing application programming interfaces (APIs).

# Department of Education, e-Learning and ICT Intern

04/2021 – 04/2023 Rustenburg, South Africa

Adding PCs to the domain. Configure new workstations, laptops, printers and any other required hardware configuration that is not covered by other contracts Conduct swap-out of existing workstations, switches, notebooks, printers, monitors and the likes Upgrade workstations, laptops and other hardware, as required, in line with existing maintenance contracts.

- Restore operating systems on workstations and laptops Desktop support and maintenance including but not limited, assisting with printer access set-up, troubling shooting user issues, assisting with logon issues, installing software, ensuring internet access, etc.

Troubleshooting – the ability to run diagnostic tests and determine the causes of errors or problems. Time management – resolving client issues in a timely manner to keep downtime to a minimum, the ability to efficiently manage own time, as I often work with little or no supervision.

Stellar proficiency in MS Office Suite SQL, System Development Life Cycle Knowledge Planning and Organizational skills — keeping track of common issues and maintaining accurate reports. Communication skills — strong verbal communication skills to discuss products and product issues with clients; written communication skills to produce reports and other paperwork. Customer relations.

## Ke A Dira Projects and Plant Hire (Pty) Ltd,

Site and Interim Project Manager
Pitching project ideas and securing approval before each project commences.

Developing new project plans in consultation with stakeholders, including clients and staff.

Outlining the human and material resources required to successfully complete each project.

Formulating a resource allocation strategy, and utilizing this to distribute work and finances.

Monitoring staff performance to ensure excellence and adherence to specified deadlines.

On-the-ground thinking and decision making.

Evaluating each project's effectiveness by consulting with clients, consumers, and staff.

Conducting continual business process reviews and proposing optimization methods.

Reporting on each project's utility upon the uptake of outputs.

07/2016 – 08/2018 Klerksdorp, South Africa

guidance and input d project.	uring the key phase of each		
Skills			
Leadership		Communication	
Collaboration talent		Problem-solving	 •

# References

Available upon request

Consulting with the assigned Project Manager to seek